字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
EPISODE 12: THE OTHER SIDE OF THE COUNTRY
（第12集：对岸的国家）
Catch anything, old man?
钓到鱼了吗 老人家？
It's nearly hibernation season for fish.
现在是鱼类休眠期
I don't mind not catching anything
钓不到也没关系
since my main work is as a ferryman.
反正我的主业是摆渡人
You're all Danish, aren't you?
你们是丹麦人吧？
You speak English well enough,
你的英语说得很好
but you've got a slight accent.
但还是有一点口音
It's similar to the accent of my country.
跟我们国家的口音有点像
How much is the ferriage to the opposite bank?
摆渡去对岸要多少钱？
Two silver coins.
两枚银币
I also take strong drink.
要是没钱的话 有酒也行
Now then, to transport you all will take several days.
不过把你们全运过去 要花很多天
No.
不 要带的只有这封信
That's too bad. I was hoping there'd be passengers.
我还以为来大客户了呢 太遗憾了
So whose the recipient on the other bank?
那么要把信送给对岸的哪位？
Deliver is now to one of the elders.
请尽快送到任何一位元老手中
Tell them it's from the son of Lydia, Askeladd.
请告诉他们 是莉迪亚之子阿谢拉特的信
Understood. I will do so promptly.
好的 我会及时送达的
Askeladd!
阿谢拉特！
Askeladd! Where are you?
阿谢拉特！你在哪儿？
Hey!
喂！
Ragnar, please be quiet.
拉格纳 请安静一点
Why have we stopped marching?
为何要停下来？
Thorkell will overtake us!
托鲁克尔会追上我们的！
When Ear is working, we must keep quiet.
大耳做事时 我们不能发出声响
Ear?
大耳？
Bjorn, stop that cone head from breathing.
表伦 把那个尖脑袋的呼吸堵住
Ear!
大耳 情况怎样？
They're closer than yesterday.
比昨天更近了
I hear footsteps and horses marching.
我听见了脚步声和马匹的行军声
Close too
将近500人
They're right behind us.
他们紧紧跟在我们后面
About a day's distance away on foot.
大概步行一天的距离
Are you sure, Ear?
你确定吗 大耳？
Yesterday you said they were two days away.
你昨天还说相差两天的距离
Are you doubting my hearing?
你在怀疑我的耳力吗？
They're quick.
好快
They're marching at a fast pace.
他们在高强度的急行前进
At this rate, they'll reach us in a few days.
照这样下去 要不了几天就被追上了
Quiet, everyone!
所有人 安静！
Horses. Two on the hill!
山上有两匹马！
We're entirely within their grasp.
我们行踪完全暴露了
What do we do?
该怎么办？
If we're to counter, we must get into formation now.
要迎击的话 现在就要排兵布阵了
No, impossible.
不 不可能的
We wouldn't succeed.
我们是赢不了的
But at this rate…
可是这样下去的话…
I've sent for reinforcements.
我已经请求了援军
For now, we'll try to shake them off here.
在到来之前 我们先尽力逃吧
-Huh? -Reinforcements?
-哈？ -援军？
Reinforcements?
援军？
We're right in enemy territory.
我们可是在敌军腹地
That's what Askeladd said, right?
阿谢拉特这么说的 对吧？
You ever hear him lie about something like this?
他以前有在这种事上说过谎吗？
I guess not. That's true.
好吧 我想没有 的确如此
But where's the nearest fort?
可离这最近的据点是哪里呢？
Leicester.
莱斯特
Are you serious?
不是吧？
It'll take us two weeks!
那要花两周才能到啊！
Will reinforcements really arrive in time?
援军来得及吗？
With more help, won't we have to share the spoils?
而且叫了援兵 赃物也要分出去吧？
Askeladd said we'd be splitting it just between the 100 of us.
阿谢拉特不是说只有咱们100个人嘛
I am so exhausted!
累死我了！
I wanna sail on a ship.
我想坐船
Yeah.
是啊
If only we had a ship.
要是有船就好了
What?
怎么？有什么事吗？
Everyone is restless.
大家都焦躁不安
You must explain what we're doing.
你得给我们说明一下
Let them be restless.
让他们焦躁吧
A little agitation is good if it spurs them to pick up the pace.
稍微着急一点 行军也能更快
What?
干什么？
If there's nothing else, go to sleep.
要是没其他事 你也去睡吧
You've been acting strangely these past few days.
你这几天有点怪怪的
What are you thinking?
你到底在想什么？
You've been like this since seeing the prince's face.
从你看到王子的脸 就开始这样了
I've been living among scoundrels for more than 40 years.
我在恶人堆里混了四十多年了
With just one glance
我只要看一眼一个人的长相
I can tell whether a man is proud or meek, clever or foolish.
就能知道他是大人物还是小人物 是聪明还是愚蠢
When I saw the prince's face,
当我看到王子那张脸时
I understood.
我就知道
He doesn't have the face of a king.
他没有王者的面相
Yeah, he looks more like a woman.
那肯定 他看着更像个女人
But you know, he's just a kid.
但你知道 他还是孩子
Well, that's true.
你说得对
He's still young.
他还年轻
It starts now.
未来可期
What does?
未来？
All right, wake up, you bastards!
好了 醒醒 你们这帮混小子！
Prepare to march!
出发 准备行军
Waste time and Thorkell will catch up!
磨蹭的话 托鲁克尔会追上我们的！
What?
不是吧？
Is he serious?
他说真的吗？
It's still pitch black out.
还一片漆黑呢
Hey.
嘿
What?
什么？
Did you sleep?
你昨晚睡了吗？
No.
没有
Hey.
嘿
You're so loud. Shut up.
你太吵了 闭嘴
But if I don't talk,
要是不说话 我会睡着的
We're in trouble, Askeladd.
我们有麻烦了 阿谢拉特
They're close.
他们已经走得很近了
Yeah, I know.
对 我知道
At this rate, they'll catch us.
这样下去 他们会追上我们的
I know that.
我知道
We're almost to the rendezvous point.
我们马上到汇合点了
See? There.
看到了吗？就在那里
They're our reinforcements?
那是我们的援军？
Two men?
才两个人？
They're not evil fog demons, right?
他们不会是雾中的恶魔吧？
I'm grateful to you for coming yourself, Commander.
劳烦指挥官亲自到来 不胜惶恐
It's been a long time, Askeladd.
好久不见 阿谢拉特
So.
然后那些人就坐船去对岸了？
Do you know whose ship it was?
知道是属于哪里的船吗？
No, I couldn't tell.
不知道 没法确定
The fog was as thick as goat's milk.
雾像山羊奶一样浓
It wasn't a Norse ship.
不是挪威人的船
There was no dragon's head.
没有龙头
Yeah, it was a stodgy-looking ship.
是的 那船看上去有点笨重
I'm sure I saw eyes painted on it.
我确定我看到上面画着眼睛
Wide eyes on the bow.
船头上画着大眼睛
That doesn't seem like King Sweyn's ship.
那看起来不像是斯韦恩国王的船
Either way, we can no longer trace the footsteps of Thorfinn and the rest.
不管怎样 再没法追踪托尔芬他们了
We may have underestimated them.
我可能有点小瞧他们了
Who knew they'd have an ally on the other side of the River Severn?
谁知道塞文河对面 会有他们的盟友呢？
Do you mean to say the people
你是说河对岸的人
across the river changed sides from England to Denmark?
背叛英格兰 加入丹麦了？
Fool. You don't know anything, do you?
蠢货 你什么都不懂 不是吗？
It doesn't matter if they changed sides. The land across the river isn't England.
根本不是背叛 对岸压根不是英格兰
That's Wales.
那是威尔士
Wales.
威尔士
A mountainous region to the west of England.
位于英格兰西面的山岳地带
Steep peaks, scarce resources,
群山陡峭 资源稀少
and little flat land suitable for farming.
适合耕种的平地极少
Compared with England, it is a barren land.
比起英格兰 可说是不毛之地
Since the fall of the Roman Empire,
在罗马帝国统治结束后
the country's regions never unified.
这个国家的各个地区从来没统一过
And several small kingdoms held their ground for hundreds of years.
数百年间一直是群雄割据
The call for help from Askeladd's army
而回应阿谢拉特救援请求的
was answered by one of those small kingdoms.
就是其中一个小国
EASTERN PART OF THE KINGDOM OF MORGANNWG, WALES
（威尔士 莫里冈库王国东部）
I commend you, Askeladd.
值得赞赏啊 阿谢拉特
Right about now, Thorkell's army must be across the river grinding their teeth.
托鲁克尔肯定正在河对岸咬牙切齿呢
All we have to do now is sail this route home to Gainsborough!
我们要做的 就是走海路回到根斯堡
No, we'll be going by land from here.
不 接下来我们走陆路
What the hell are you talking about? There are ships right here!
你在鬼扯什么？
Consider it from the perspective of a small nation.
请不要以军事大国的标准来看待他们
Three warships in this country hold great military value.
对他们而言 三艘战舰是宝贵的战力
We must be grateful they helped us escape Thorkell.
能帮我们摆脱托鲁克尔 就该满足了
Then how about two ships? We can squeeze in 100 if we try.
那两艘船怎么样？一百人挤得下
No. And I'll leave you behind if you act like a spoiled child.
不行 再说这种任性的孩子话 就把你留在这里
You're telling us to walk through Wales?
你叫我们步行穿过威尔士？
Inconceivable!
你疯了！
The people here hate us.
这里的人痛恨我们
I will not let you subject His Highness to any further danger!
我绝不会再让殿下陷入危险！
A falcon.
猎鹰…
Flying so low.
飞得这么低…
Ragnar, capture it for me.
拉格纳 给我抓一只
What? Your Highness, we're…
什么？殿下
discussing something crucial.
我们正在谈重要的事
It's better than heading north to England with Thorkell on our tail.
总比北上去英格兰 还被托鲁克尔追赶好得多
At least I have allies in this country.
至少在这个国家 我有盟友
If you're still worried, then…
如果你还是担心…
Thorfinn!
托尔芬！
I will have this one escort the prince.
我派这个人当殿下的护卫
You're the boy from before.
你是之前的那个男孩…
Don't make decisions for me.
别擅自为我做决定
He's small but very skilled.
虽然个子小 但身手过人
He's the same age as the prince, so they'll get along.
他和王子年岁相同 会相处融洽的
Greet him, Thorfinn.
来打个招呼 托尔芬
You idiot!
蠢货！
What are doing glaring at him like that?
你这么瞪着他想干嘛？
I'll be compensated, right?
我会得到回报的 对吧？
All right.
好吧
We'll duel upon reaching Gainsborough.
到了根斯堡 我就和你决斗
Askeladd, are you ready?
阿谢拉特 准备好了吗？
Yes, soon.
是的 这就好
It never stops.
天啊 我真是太忙了
This is the commander of the Kingdom of Morgannwg, Gratianus.
这位是莫里冈库王国的将军 格拉蒂亚诺阁下
He will lead us through the route.
他会带我们穿过这条路线
He seems harsh, but is a strong-looking young man.
他看来很冷峻 但是个帅气的年轻人
Commander, that's one of my men.
指挥官 那是我的部下
Prince Canute is over there.
克努特王子在那边
His gaze lacks fortitude.
他的眼神很无力
Can this be the next generation to lead England?
他真是下一代的英格兰统治者吗？
What? How dare you!
什么？你真是失礼！
We only have one reason for helping the Danish Prince escape.
我们协助丹麦王子逃跑理由只有一个
Wales wishes to enter a non-aggression pact.
威尔士希望与你们缔结不可侵犯条约
Everything depends on you.
一切看你的决定了
Prince, swear to us
王子 我要你向我们发誓
that upon becoming the king of England,
当你成为英格兰之王时
you will not interfere with the affairs of Wales.
绝对不会干预威尔士
I'll take care of this.
好的 包在我身上
His Highness has stated the following:
殿下是这么说的
"If you offer us three ships--"
“如果你们愿意提供三艘船…”
I'm asking the prince directly.
我是在问王子本人
What?
什么？
In that case, I'll ask him again later.
罢了 我稍后再来问
In the meantime, I will prepare the documents.
在此期间 我先去准备公函
Quickly, assemble for departure.
尽快做好出发准备
How can he be so insolent?
怎会有如此傲慢自大之人？
He's taking advantage of us!
他想趁机占我们的便宜！
Does he think he can speak to the prince as an equal?
他以为他有资格和殿下平等对话吗？
The damned provincial fool!
该死的乡巴佬！
Marching, marching, and more marching.
行军 行军 又是行军
And now there's a mountain road.
现在还有一条山路
A mountain road is better than facing Thorkell.
总比面对托鲁克尔好多了
Let's talk about something fun.
我们聊点开心的事吧
Like what?
比如呢？
The rewards we'll get from King Sweyn.
我们从斯韦恩国王那里得到的奖励
Saving the prince from Thorkell has gotta be worth a lot.
我们可是从托鲁克尔手中 救出了王子啊
-I'd like to get a whole farm. -A fine sword would be nice.
我想要得到一整座农场
No, I want gold.
不 我要黄金
There's nothing that beats gold.
没什么比金子更好
That's the truth.
你说得对！
I heard that in his bedroom the king has 100 of the most beautiful concubines
我听说在国王的寝宫里
Now, that gets me excited! Tell me more!
想想就兴奋！还有什么？
Hey, Father!
喂 神父！
You've been to the royal palace, right?
你在王宫里待过吧？
What's inside the king's chambers?
国王的家里都有什么啊？
Well…
这个嘛 没什么特别值钱的东西
It can't be! Not even women?
不是吧 连女人都没有吗？
Yes, there were quite a few female slaves.
是的 女性奴隶挺多的
He says that so casually.
他说得倒挺轻巧…
You're not interested in women?
你对女人没兴趣吗？
No.
不不不
Compared to that which I seek
只是和我想要的东西相比
money and women mean nothing.
金钱和女人都微不足道
Tell us please.
那请你说说
What is it you seek?
你追求的是什么？
Love.
是爱
Huh? Love?
-哈？爱？ -是的
What's that? I've never heard of it.
那是什么？我从没听说过
I have.
我知道
It's some magic word that Christians always say.
那是基督徒常说的类似魔咒的东西
It's not food?
不是吃的啊？
How many pounds of silver is it worth?
用银子换算的话 值几磅啊？
It cannot be measured in silver.
没法用银子来衡量
Because love is what gives silver value.
因为是爱给予银子价值的
Gold, silver, women, and everything else have no value without love.
黄金、白银、女人和其他一切 没有爱就毫无价值
It gives value?
给予价值？
I don't think I get it.
我完全听不懂
Silver is worth silver.
银子不是有它自身的价值嘛
Why make things complicated?
为什么让事情复杂化？
He's probably making it up.
他一定是在虚张声势
Forget him.
别搭理他了
Hey, monk.
喂 修道士
Say more about it.
继续刚才的话
I'm interested.
我还想再听听
We should be entering Brycheiniog soon.
马上要进入不列颠尼奥古王国了
Don't worry. I've spoken to them.
不用担心 我已经和他们谈过了
I appreciate your support.
很感激您的努力协助
We're not doing this for you. It's in our best interest as well.
我们不是为了你们 对我们也有好处
For a long time, the Welsh kingdoms have suffered the invasions of England.
威尔士诸国长久以来
If you Danes can force them into submission, it works in our favor.
如果你们丹麦人能使他们屈服
The Prince will surely promise to make that happen.
王子殿下一定会答应的
Is that your king, Askeladd?
那就是你的国王吗 阿谢拉特？
The bloodline is good.
我不反对血统
And as he is still young there is much we can expect.
除此之外 能期待的就是他的成长了
The more charmed you are by a man, the less likely things will go your way.
越是看上的男人 往往无法如我所愿
But he may surprise us and turn out to be the perfect vessel.
说不定他刚好能具有完美的器量
We are the proud descendants of Britannia.
我们是荣耀的不列颠尼亚的后裔
We will not follow a Danish king.
不会服从丹麦的国王的
Gratianus.
格拉蒂亚诺
Do you still believe in that legend?
您还在相信那传说吗？
The one that claims Artorius will return from Avalon in the far west
阿托利斯会从遥远西方的阿瓦隆归来
and revive the Britannia of old.
复兴古老不列颠尼亚
Askeladd!
阿谢拉特！
You're certain?
确定吗？
That's what Ear said.
大耳是这么说的
You've done well to travel this far, Prince of Denmark!
丹麦王子 你很厉害 长途跋涉而来！
An envoy from Brycheiniog.
那是不列颠尼奥古的使者
Greetings to you!
感谢你来迎接我们
Wait, Gratianus.
等等 格拉蒂亚诺
Did they notice?
被他们注意到了吗？
How do you know?
你怎么知道的？
I have a man with superb hearing.
我的部下中 有听觉灵敏的人
But they're too late.
但为时已晚了
What's wrong, Thorfinn?
怎么了 托尔芬？
Stand up! Quickly!
站起来！快！
Let's go.
我们走